

## Profile

I am an experienced full stack developer who has a proven track record of producing quality code for production releases. I have published apps in the Google Play Store, the Apple App Store, the Overwolf store, and I have built production web apps from scratch. I also love to learn and I am capable of picking up new skills to fill any positional requirements.

## Employment History

## Lead Front End Developer at Liifer Technologies, Remote

May 2021 — November 2023

- In this position I wrote roughly 95% of the front end code that would end up in the production applications. I also made the decisions for front end stack, which includes React, Typescript, and Tailwind CSS.
- I selected and implemented the many modern libraries and tools included in the application. This includes but is not limited to: react-query, redux, react-router, axios, i18next, react-hook-form, react-table, google services API, Overwolf API, Ionic Capacitor, and react-testing-library.
- The back-end of the application is a REST API. This API has dozens
  of endpoints and is capable of everything you would expect from
  a modern food delivery application. The front end is connected to
  the endpoints using axios and custom React hooks created with
  react-query.
- This app proved efficient enough to used in an Overwolf extension, which allows gamers to order food while in-game, without slowing the performance of their PC. This app is currently available in the Overwolf store.
- I also ported this application to IOS and Android, through Ionic Capacitor. These ports passed verification and are available in the Apple App Store and the Google Play store.

#### Freelance Web Developer at SeonVision, Montréal

March 2021 — May 2021

- For this short-term contracted position, I built a landing page for a small start-up company for their application called SeonTaste. To do this I used tailwind CSS and React.
- I also did some work on their React Native application, which had been built by another contractor.

#### **Details**

Halifax, Nova Scotia Canada 1 (514) 233-4794 stephen.ricketts.dev@gmail.com

#### Links

stevedev.co liifer.com github.com/StephenRicketts

#### **Skills**

React

**TypeScript** 

Tailwind CSS

Next.js

**React Native** 

node.js

MongoDB

HTML & CSS

Git

Jira

Figma

**Ionic Capacitor** 

Electron

### Education

## Diploma in Full-Stack Web Development, Concordia University, Montréal

September 2019 — December 2019

Completed 480+ hours of intensive full-stack web development course focused on programming fundamentals including test-driven development, object-oriented programming, SCRUM, Agile methodologies, pair-programming, algorithms and databases, with a focus on React and JavaScript.

# Bachelor of Arts, Psychology, University of New Brunswick, Fredericton, New Brunswick

September 2008 — May 2012

## Courses

React Native - The Practical Guide, Udemy

September 2020 — December 2020

React and TypeScript: Build a Portfolio Project (2021), Udemy

January 2021 — February 2021

## **◄** References

Patrick Ostiguy from Liifer

patrick@liifer.com

David Ostiguy from Liifer

david.ostiguy@liifer.com

Louis-Philippe Ostiguy from Liifer

louis-philippe@liifer.com